Visual AIDS Institutional Records
Visual AIDS Archive
- Projects
  - Public Programs
    - Eric Rhein Box Office Materials, 2011 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Mark Morrisroe Program, 2011 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - "Kingsbridge and the Devil" Mural Materials, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - "Radically Gay: The Life & Visionary Legacy of Harry Hay" Materials, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - 2012 Public Programs (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - 2013 Public Programs (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - International Curatorial Residency, 2013 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - "Patriot" Mural Materials, 2014 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - 2014 Public Programs (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - International Curatorial Residency, 2014 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - New York Art Book Fair, 2014 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - "Art, AIDS, America" Materials, 2014-2016 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - 2015 Public Programs (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Folsom Street East Festival, 2015 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - 2016 Public Programs (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - 2017 Public Programs (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Los Angeles Art Book Fair, 2017 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - 2018 Public Programs (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Love Positive Women, 2018-2020 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - 2019 Public Programs (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - "Broadcast" Screening Series Material, 2022 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Publications
    Visual AIDS's publishing program produces books that highlight underknown artists and preserve legacies that might otherwise be lost. Publication types include monographs, exhibition catalogs, and the "Duets: In Conversation" series. Duets pairs artists, activists, writers, and thinkers in dialogues about their creative practices and current social issues related to HIV/AIDS.
    Materials pertaining to Visual AIDS publications contain planning materials, proofs, promotional materials, and published comic books. These materials are dated 1995-2021.
    - Andres & Tony, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - "Bearing Witness (to AIDS)" Materials, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Hugh Steers Book Materials, 2012-2016 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Duets 1 and 2 (Dzubilo and Andrews), 2014 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Duets 3 and 4 (Cuevas and Moufarrege), 2016 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Duets 7 (Weston), 2021 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Red Ribbon Project
    In 1991 a group of artists known as the Visual AIDS Artists' Caucus came together to create a meaningful symbol to show support and compassion for those with AIDS and their caregivers at the height of the crisis. They created what was titled "The Ribbon Project," better known today simply as the Red Ribbon. Through a series of meetings in April and May of 1991, the Red Ribbon was born. The color red was chosen for its "connection to blood and the idea of passion - not only anger but love".
    Visual AIDS partnered with Broadway Cares and Equity Fights AIDS in June 1991 to adorn guests and presenters at the 45th Annual Tony Awards. The red ribbon quickly became renowned as an international symbol of AIDS awareness, and has been worn at the Oscars, Emmys, and Grammys; celebrities, musicians, athletes, artists, and politicians have worn the ribbon on talk shows, TV programs, movies, political conventions, sporting events, and music videos.
    Today the red ribbon is an internationally recognized symbol of AIDS awareness and a design icon. It has led the way for many other color ribbons and awareness projects. Unlike some other commercial marketing campaigns, the red ribbon originally evolved as an artists/activist project and it has never been copyrighted.
    Materials pertaining to the Red Ribbon Project include production materials, photographs, promotional materials, press clippings, correspondence, loan agreements, and exhibition announcements. This material is dated 1991-2021.
    - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Honorary Committee Materials, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Outreach Letters (Tony Awards), 1991 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Press Clippings, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Production Materials, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Press Releases, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - 35mm Slides, 1991-2008 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Celebrity Ribbon Cavalcade Material, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Photographs, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Publicity Letters, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Press Clippings, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Press Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Stamp Campaign, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Promotional Materials, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Press Clippings, 1994-2002 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - "Lessons from the Red Ribbon", 1997 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Cooper Hewitt Design Museum Exhibition Announcements, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence (RE: New York Times Misattribution), 1997 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence (Misattribution), 1998 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - History, 2003-2011 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Press Clippings, 2003-2011 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Loan Agreements, 2004-2021 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - MoMA Correspondence, 2015 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Fundraising
  - Benefit Events
    The Benefit Events series contains announcements, documentation, and internal records related to Visual AIDS fundraising events. Since 2006, Visual AIDS's primary benefit event has been the Visual AIDS Vanguard Awards (VAVA Voom), a gala that recognizes the achievements and contributions of individuals who strengthen the cultural history of art, AIDS and activism in our community.
    Materials pertaining to Visual AIDS benefits include exhibition announcements, invitations, correspondence, advertisements, press clippings, and planning materials. These materials are dated 1998-2018.
    - Dada Ball, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Studio 24 Exhibition Materials, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - The Lure Materials, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - "May Day" Materials, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - La Maison de Sade Materials, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - 45 Bleecker Theater Materials, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - "A Big Hairy Deal" Materials, 2002-2004 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - "Lost and Found" Materials, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - "Strike!" Materials, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - "Strike 2!" Materials, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - "Strike 3!" Materials, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - VAVA Voom, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - VAVA Voom, 2014 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Christopher Tanner Auction Event Invitation, 2015 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - VAVA Voom, 2015 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Planning Materials, 2017 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - John Laub Memorial Materials, 2018 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - VAVA Voom, 2018 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - VAVA Voom, 2020 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Pride Benefit Party, 2023 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Benefit Prints
    Visual AIDS published limited edition prints by renowned contemporary artists as part of its fundraising efforts.
    Materials pertaining to benefit prints include promotional materials, correspondence, press clippings, and planning materials. These materials are dated 2012-2022.
    - Ligon, Glenn, 2012 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Taaffe, Philip, 2013 (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Planning Materials, 2013-2016 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Kass, Deborah, 2014 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Muholi, Zanele, 2014 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Feher, Tony, 2015 (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Loewe Capsule Collection Press Clippings, 2018 (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Silence = Death, 2021 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Langberg, Doron, 2022 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Postcards from the Edge
    Since 1998, Visual AIDS has produced the annual Postcards From the Edge exhibition and benefit. For this fundraiser, Visual AIDS solicits original, postcard-sized works on paper by established and emerging artists.
    Materials pertaining to Postcards from the Edge contain promotional materials and exhibition announcements. These materials are dated 1998-2022.
    - Postcards from the Edge, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2013 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2014 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2015 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2016 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2018 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Postcards from the Edge, 2022 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Collected HIV/AIDS Historical Materials
  The Collected HIV/AIDS Historical Materials series has materials related to HIV/AIDS art and activism that have been collected by Visual AIDS staff but not produced by the organization or its artist members. The materials include those produced by individuals as well as by other HIV/AIDS organizations.
  Materials in this series include photographs, 35mm slides, press clippings, ephemera, collectible materials, printed artworks, and exhibition materials. These materials are dated 1988-2020.
  - Condoms (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Gran Fury Materials, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Print Projects (1 of 2), 1989-2011 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Print Projects (2 of 2), 1989-2011 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Artist Member Press Clippings, 1993-2014 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - The Names Project Materials, 1994-1998 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Press Clippings, 1996-2013 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Printed Artworks, 2004-2013 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Institute of Cultural Inquiry "Forget Foucault" Buttons, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Foundational Sharing 4, 2013 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Foundational Sharing 5, 2013 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Foundational Sharing 6, 2014 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Foundational Sharing 8, 2015 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - HIV Howler, 2018-2019 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - AIDS Activism Photographs
    - Neipris, Ellen B, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - AIDS Demonstration, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - McGovern, Tim, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - McAdams, Dona Ann, 1988-1990 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Eberle, Todd, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Incerti, W Benjamin, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Propaganda Art, 1991-1993 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Exhibitions
    - "Brian Weil: The AIDS Photographs" Materials, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Exhibition Materials, 1996-2020 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - "What Now?" Materials, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "Recovering the Positives: Originals" Materials, 2001-2002 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Proof Positive" Materials, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - "Blanchon & Andrews" Materials, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - "AIDS Over Time/Time Over AIDS" Materials, 2014 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - "99 Objects" Materials, 2015 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - "Art After Stonewall" Materials, 2016 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - "Pickle Surprise" Materials, 2016 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - "positive/negative: HIV/AIDS" Materials, 2016 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - "Things" Materials, 2016 (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - "AIDS at Home" Materials, 2017 (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - "Catalyst: Art and Social Justice" Materials, 2020-2021 (Box 10, Folder 49)